I'm Shubham.
I lead the Harness AI
initiatives in Harness.
Before I jump in into the presentation,
I would just like to spend a couple of
minutes around what Harness is about so
that you get a brief idea of what we do.
So Harness is, most of you guys
might have seen or read about it.
It's in the DevSecOps sector.
Anything related to-- So you write your
code in your IDs, in your Cursor, Cloud
codes of the world, and Harness takes
care of the-- takes care of shipping
your code from your like, from creating
a PR to writing a CI pipeline, to writing
a continuous deployment pipeline, to
testing it, to taking it to production.
So it takes care of your entire DevOps
life cycle, takes care of securing
your code when it is being deployed.
So i-it's like you just write the code and
leave it to Harness, and Harness will take
care of everything or whatever your code
needs, be it Docker images, artifacts,
everything, and taking it into production.
Specifically on the Harness AI side,
we are trying to reinvent and rethink
on how we can use AI for DevOps so
that the outer loop for deployment
after writing code becomes much faster.
Because as we have seen, writing
code has become super fast
increase at a blazing speed.
But deploying it still takes time
because there are a lot of approvals.
It goes through a lot of pipelines,
deployment and all of that.
So we are trying to use AI for DevOps
and trying to see how we can increase
the life cycle of our deployment of your
changes to production as soon as possible.
Cool.
I'll jump into the presentation.
Today I'm going to talk about so
AI for POCs are easy, but when you
start taking your AI product to
pro-production, it becomes hard.
So the talk is going to be about
the enterprise AI blueprint.
How should you think about taking your AI
agents, whatever you're building on AI,
to production and selling it to customers?
Moving on as I mentioned, AI
demos versus enterprise AI.
You might have often seen AI demos, you
just come up with a plan, what you want
to do, think about it, come up with a
plan, and it takes days or weeks to build.
It wows everyone in the group who
you're-- whom you're presenting, and
they would want you to repla- deploy your
AI in production as soon as possible.
But that's where it fails because
enterprise AI, when you want to
take AI to production and give it to
customers, it needs robust architecture.
It needs consistency and reliability
so that your customers don't complain
about your AI is not working for
this use case versus this use case.
It is taking some random actions
which it was not intending to, your
AI going rogue and all of that.
And when you do demos, you are not
throwing your AI at a large data.
So you majorly focus on the prompt
engineering, making sure the
demos look cool and wow everyone.
But when it-- when you actually want
to take it to production, it has to
work on good amount of data as well.
So it-- the mindset shifts from prompt
engineering to context engineering,
how well you can engineer the context
so that your AI stays grounded and
works what you have asked it to.
And yeah, ninety percent of the prototypes
fail to scale in the enterprises
because it lacks all of these, the
robust architecture, consistency,
context engineering, a lot more I'll
cover in the later part in the slides.
So scaling enterprise AI I
see them in four pillars.
We have built all of these
four pillars in Harness.
Starting with the first one,
it's-- of course, is the context.
Context is the new code for AI these days.
Stop prompt engineering.
I think we have moved away from the
world of prompt engineering and come to
a world where it's more about building
the right knowledge base and context
engineering that knowledge page base.
Models have become so amazing that
prompt-- just the prompt engineering
won't really help you out now.
So the idea is create a living
knowledge graph from whatever
scatt-scattered data and tools you have.
Ground AI decisions in truth,
not let AI hallucinate.
So it's-- you should not
always say the model is bad.
The models are actually
doing amazingly good.
It's more how you engineer the context
so that your AI does not hallucinate
the second pillar is the evals for AI.
How do you test AI?
How do you know your AI is
actually doing good in production?
How do you catch failures when
you're making changes in the code,
in your AI code, how do you catch
failures soon enough so that your
users are not impacted by it?
And how do you create a feedback loop?
If folks are getting impacted
by it, how do you know?
And once how do you keep--
create a feedback loop so
that it does not happen again.
The third piece is the
personal- personalization.
I'm talking about memories here.
So make AI indispensable,
not generic with any query.
If, let's say, I'm working on GitHub,
or if, let's say, I'm working on
Harness itself some like Harness,
but specifically on the CD or the CI
pipeline stuff, it should remember
what I have been doing with AI.
It should not always start from scratch.
So teach AI your organization
knowledge and roles.
And the last piece, which enterprise care
about a lot, and this is the most boring
piece I say, it's governance and safety.
Enterprises care a lot about the
role, control, who can get access to
AI, what your AI can do versus cannot
do, what all access can AI have.
That is like the scariest
part in the world today.
So how do you tackle compliance?
How do you tackle privacy?
What type of sensitive
data are you passing to AI?
Because you-- we get a lot of questions
from our customers, enterprise customers
that, "Are you sending the sensitive
data to LLMs? How are you tackling it?
How are you making sure that it is not
taking rogue actions, bringing down
your production database?" We have all
seen examples of that in the world.
So th-this forms the four pillars
of building your enterprise AI.
I'll double-click in each of
them one by one, and yeah.
Starting with the context.
Context is the king in the LLM era.
The context challenge in enterprise AI,
which we also face in Harness because
Harness has a lot of product modules.
We-- I just talked about CI.
CI is one big product.
CD is another big product.
Then we also let folks create PRs
just like you create PRs on GitHub.
So things are siloed.
There is siloed data everywhere,
information is trapped in different
systems, information is trapped in
siloed Confluence, some siloed databases
which the entire AI is not aware about.
Then lack of domain knowledge.
LLMs are generic.
They are trained on all the data in
the world, so they don't understand
the specific jargons or the
processes you have in your ecosystem.
So CI in Harness could mean the CI term
in DevOps could very well mean different
as a CI term in different ecosystem.
So LLMs don't understand your
company's specific jargons or
your company's specific products.
They are generic.
Third is risk of hallu-hallucinations.
A-AI, you have to ground your AI.
Otherwise it will hallucinate and generate
misleading information very confidently.
And the fourth, as I mentioned,
the security and privacy risk.
Sharing sensitive data with external
models is risky and could lead
to, say, significant threats.
So how do you solve all of
these problems in the context?
As I said, context is the new code.
So you start with, of course,
organizational intelligence.
You consolidate different data,
different intelligence you have siloed in
different places into a unified platform.
AI should be able to query different
data you have across the board
and not think of AI as silos.
The s-second part, how do you do that?
You have to think about a knowledge graph.
It's like a living relationship,
living graph between your entities.
To give an example, so when
I'm writing code, I raise a PR.
The PR goes through certain checks,
then it gets deployed, and then it goes
through multiple cycles of production.
So if-- And then certain thing fails.
You get some prod alerts, incidents
PagerDuty on-calls, and all of that.
So if I-- if you want to ask AI a very
basic question, which of my PRs caused
incident in the last month or last week?
How do you do that?
Because it is passing through
four, five different phases.
It is passing through creating a PR.
It is passing through a CI/CD.
The issues could have been
anywhere in terms of what is being
deployed, what version is being
deployed, what commits went into
the changes, and why did it fail.
So if you have a graph, knowledge graph
between all of your data, if you imagine
it as like a graph, AI will really
rock in terms of walking through the
graph and giving you the right answers.
Knowledge graph is one of the
beautiful way to keep your AI grounded.
Third is memories.
Memories power a lot
of the context as well.
You have to teach your AI what you're
doing, and you have to distinguish between
short-term memories, long-term memories.
Memories just like-- work
just like our brain work.
We have short-term memories,
we do have long-term memories.
There are certain things
we remember for long.
we remember for short-term.
And the fourth is this--
fourth is the tools.
Tools are the most… You have heard
about MCPs in the world, and so those
are the tools I'm talking about.
So tools power the context.
Tools are also part of the context in
order for AI to take specific actions,
in order for AI to query more data.
S-So knowledge graph is only-- will
only make sense for the data you have.
But if you still want external data,
let's say from third-party sources,
you would still have to throw
tools at it and get data from it.
And all of this, you have to really
context engineer it well because LLMs
usually have-- we have seen we all know
it's either has a limit of two hundred
K tokens and now we have started to
seeing one million tokens on the LLM.
So it all depends on us how well
information you can fit into
that one million context window.
Okay.
Moving into how do you really
do context engineering?
There are certain few tips and tricks
of doing the right context engineering.
The first one is the most obvious one,
which a lot of the AI agents actually do.
So
So imagine like you're talking
to an AI chatbot, like ChatGPT
or a CloudCode or anybody.
You are talking, you are conversing,
you're asking some questions,
and the context is growing.
And the context is almost about to hit
eighty percent of the context window.
What they do is they summarize the
entire conversation, they compact it.
They take the key decisions out from it,
whatever you have been talking about.
Think of it like a garbage collector.
Like, whatever the garbage
you don't need, throw it away.
What is the important pieces
you need in your conversation,
you keep it in the context.
And then once you summarize, it
goes back again to, let's say,
twenty K tokens to thirty K tokens
de-depending on your summary
Second is the major
contributor of context bloat.
So giving an example, let's say
you have connected GitHub or
Jira Atlassian to your AI agent.
Now, you have asked it, "Can you show
me a list of Jira I worked in last
month, and what is the status for it?"
It will go make a Jira API call, Jira
MCP call, and give you a huge JSON list
of these are all the Jiras, these are
all the Jira description, these are
all the Jira comments, and all of it.
If you throw the entire output in
the context window, it's not going
to work at all because you just
took up the entire context window.
So there are certain tips and tricks
to not throw it in the context window,
rather throw it into the external files.
So whenever you are getting a large
output, dump it into the external
files, throw the agent to go and
read those files line by line or
certain sections of the line, rather
than reading the entire file again.
And the agents are again amazing
at reading the certain specific
portions and reason about why.
For example, I am analyzing
a big stack trace.
So I'll just throw it in a file.
And I have asked agent, "Can you
look at the error logs, and can you
tell me what is happening? Can you
summarize? Can you give me an RCA?"
The agents, the LLMs are smart to
look at what part of the file to
read instead of the entire file.
So just insert summaries or some semantic
references in the context window.
Don't dump the large output in
the context window directly.
The third piece is an interesting one.
It came from Anthropic, context editing.
It is a proactive approach for compaction.
So what I mean by that is, let's
suppose you have a repository.
You have asked it to-- You have
asked the Claude code or Cursor to,
"Can you go and build and test this
repository?" Just a basic question.
Now, the agent will figure it out.
It may-- Let's say it's
doing a Gradle build.
It's figuring out the right command.
The g-- And it ran the
command, it errored out.
Then it figured it out again.
"Okay, I need this argument."
Then it errored out.
It, And then it is figuring
out the right command again.
So you don't need all of the
things you have just done above
because those are not the right
commands to build the repository.
So you keep on removing irrelevant
context as you progress from the
context so that you proactively keep
your context healthy rather than always
relying on compaction at the end.
And the last piece is the
semantic augmentation.
If you have also heard of
skills which which again came
from Anthropic as a standard.
So you don't really have to throw all the
context at once in the context window.
You let LLM semantically look for those
skills or content as it goes along,
rather than dumping all of it in the
system prompt, rather than dumping
all of it in the context window.
And why it matters, it optimizes your
token costs because you are very--
you're very smart about what you are
putting into the context versus what
you're not putting into the context.
You're very smart about progressively
semantically augmenting things in
the context window, rather than
just dumping everything in the
context window and saying the LLM
is bad or the AI is hallucinating.
And these, if you follow like even if
you ignore context editing, if you follow
compaction, that's the easiest one.
The large outputs, dumping
them into the files and just
let agent look at those files.
And the last piece, the
semantic augmentation.
You would definitely see an improvement.
I can even claim you can definitely
see an improvement like eighty to
ninety percent in terms of accuracy
in your token co-- token costs
How do you go about
building a knowledge graph?
As I just mentioned, you-- the
data is present at multiple places.
It is present in code, it is present
in your docs, it is present in your
logs, it is present in your Jira
somewhere in Confluence documents.
You maintain your configs
at a different repo.
So what do you do?
You sit down, you figure out
what are all the entities I care
about in my entire ecosystem.
I care about services,
I care about my users.
Depends from use case to use case.
I care about my incidents.
Then you enrich those entities
with metadata, like who is
the owner for the entity.
Again, it depends on your use case,
but the idea is you extract entities
first as a first-class thing.
Then you enrich those entities
with certain metadata.
Then you make a graph out of those
entities, like a user is linked to
a service, or a user is linked to
an incident, or a particular release
version is in linked to an incident.
So you can have a graph who owns what,
what depends on what, and just expose
it via Graphi-API to the AI agents.
It co-- So it will be able to
then query the entire graph, walk through
the graph, filter down a sub-graph,
get the data, and then work on it.
If you don't have knowledge graph,
what you would be doing is, let's
say you didn't have knowledge graph,
there were three data sources.
The AI agent will look
at first data source.
It will have huge amount of data.
Then it will look at second source.
It will again have huge amount of data.
The agent will try to link the
relationships on there itself, and
they might hallucinate, because again,
they don't understand the relationships
which you have in your ecosystem.
They are generic LLMs.
They don't understand your
organization knowledge.
So this is the most critical part.
If you have an ecosystem where
your data is siloed and data
is at at different data sources
If context is a new code, knowledge
graph is the compiler for it.
So yeah
Moving on to personalization.
Memories is the only key
piece for personalization.
It gets its-- get its own space from
context because it needs its dedica--
it needs a dedicated investment
in itself to power memories.
And there are different types of memories.
There is short-term memory, like
the one we are just doing as a call.
You guys might remember what I
just said for a short term, but
you will take away some long-term
memories as a part of this meetup.
So think of it from that an-that angle.
Short-term memory is what you're
able to retain as you go along in
the AI when you're chatting with AI.
Long-term memories is when you
start bubbling up the short-term
memories into long-term memories.
For example, this user asks a lot of
questions about why are my logs failing.
This user actively works on GitHub.
This team actively works on these repos.
So you can bubble up some of the
memories as long-term memories and
as you as I mentioned out, chatbots
forget, assistants remember.
That's why we call it AI
assistant, not really AI chatbot.
Memories give you multiple things.
It powers your context,
it maintains continuity.
It does not start again from fresh.
It already remembers what you have
done before, and that brings it-- that
brings in confidence to your end users
who are using the AI you have built.
And context makes AI relevant,
memory makes it human.
It makes it feel like it is
remembering, and that's what
we humans are also amazing at
Yeah.
Chatbots talk, assistants collaborate.
So imagine like you are, let's say,
building an AI chat for your ecosystem.
If you just throw in an AI chat
as a pop-up on the right, which
you might have mostly seen in
different products, now there's an
AI chat pop up on the bottom right.
And if it is just working independently,
it is not understanding what screen
you are on, where are you navigating.
And if it is just acting independently,
users will feel out of place that I am
on this particular page of this product,
why is my AI not talking about this page?
Taking it to the next level, you should
also think about it as an assistant.
If I am on a certain page, for example,
I want to generate a CI pipeline, CI for
my code, and I am on a CI screen where
I'm building the pipeline, I'm writing
unit tests, I'm writing integration
tests, I'm writing security test.
You-- It would be amazing if you
are able to ask the AI chat, "Can
you create a CI pipeline for me and
validate if it is working or not?
Run it.
If it errors out, fix it.
Try to fig-- run it again." And if it
is able to do it interactively in your
AI app, that brings a lot of power
when you expose AI to the customer.
So think of AI not as an independent
thing in your product, but
rather it should collaborate.
Just like-- Again, like when you write
code with Cursor or Cloud Code, it--
you see what the code is writing.
The AI chat is also able to understand
what the changes it is making, what
the changes you are making in the code.
So I'm just painting that
anal-analogy on any of the products
you want to throw the AI on it.
So basically, the idea is it
should be able to take actions
back in the app, understand the app
context, and then further go along.
And that's how we have seen
the AI world evolve, right?
It's in last year, last to last year
when all of it started it as a chatbot.
But then we saw the evaluation,
e-evolution of AI from AI chatbot to AI
assistants when it is able to take actions
in your app, and it is able to go along
And the third piece of the evolution
of AI is the autonomous agent.
So I'll again walk through the
evolution of AI since we have
seen it from last couple of years.
Started with a chatbot,
started with the basic prompts.
It handles basic single predefined
tasks, no, no good context or awareness.
Then it went into assistant mode.
It is able to understand
what you're talking about.
It is able to take guided actions
within work-- within your workflow.
And in the current era, in the current
past few months, AI has also started
evolving into an autonomous agents.
So might have heard of Claude Cowork or
Cursor agents, where it is like there is
no human also interacting with the AI.
It's like it's listening on some trigger.
It starts working on it, takes some
actions, maybe or may not be wait on
your approval, and just get done with it.
So for example, I have an autonomous
agent which runs every day at ten
AM, looks at my Slack, looks at my
email, looks at my Jira, everything.
Figures out what all messages should
I look at, what is my priority to look
at today versus not look at later in
the day, what actions should I take.
And it is an autonomous agent which runs
every day at ten AM and just gives me a
nice page of what should I look at today
versus what are my priorities for today.
A second example for autonomous
agent could be, I keep coming back
to the example of raising a PR
and there is a CI running in it.
So imagine you as a developer
are working on a code.
You raise a PR for it.
Now the check starts running,
the unit test, the integration
test, the security test, and they
do take their own sweet time.
They do take twenty minutes,
thirty minutes to run, depending
on how heavy are your tests.
But you cannot-- You are not waiting for
twenty, thirty minutes and just looking
at it and waiting for it to fail or pass.
You go and pick up a different work.
Now, when it fails, you get notified.
You have to stop your work, come
back, go and fix your failures,
raise and-- raise the fix again.
Again, wait for it.
So that's very tedious.
That's like a toil in your usual workflow.
Imagine there was an autonomous agent
where you just raise a PR, the CI is
running, and the agent is listening
and keeping it-- keeping an eye on your
PR, whether the CI is failing or not.
If it is failing, it is
automatically figuring out what
are the fixes needed, committing
it, making sure your PR is green.
So you don't really have
to do anything else.
You just focus on your next work and let
the autonomous agents take care of it.
So that's what I'm talking about here.
And yeah, coming with a quote again,
"If assistants are copilots, autonomous
agents are like your teammates."
Okay.
Coming to the most important
piece for doing AI.
This is like after context, I would not
even keep memories as a second thing.
I would keep evals as the second most
important thing to focus on for your AI.
What are evals?
Evals are just like your unit tests for
AI, but there is a difference between
how you were writing unit tests or
integration tests for your normal software
because that was a deterministic code.
You know what happens next, you know
what the code is going to do next.
So you're-- you were able to write
a better deterministic unit tests or
integration tests on top of your software.
In AI, it's not the case.
It is not deterministic.
A lot of the outputs are probabilistic.
So the traditional unit
test mindsets don't apply.
And we have seen like most teams skip
evals because it is very hard to define
what good looks like for an AI agent.
How do you know what is
good versus what is bad?
But without any kind of test,
I'm not even talking about AI.
Imagine you're writing a software
system, but you're not writing
tests at all, any sorts of tests.
You are just throwing some code to
the customer where you don't even
know what's going to happen, and it--
your users are just going to throw
away your product quickly because
it's not working as you expected.
So eval's mindset is the most
important mindset to have when
you are building any AI ecosystem.
It quantifies trust.
It gives you confidence
on how it is doing.
It gives you confidence on when
you are making changes in the code,
there are no regressions going.
And so I'll give you a very basic example.
Let's say I have created an AI agent
which is wor-working very well with
Opus because Opus is one of the most
amazing frontier models in the world.
But I realize that it is burning a lot
of tokens, a lot of cost, and I want
to switch it to Sonnet now, or I want
to switch it to OpenAI for that matter.
How can you confidently
switch it to Sonnet?
You cannot just go and change the
model name and say it will work best.
It won't.
And you cannot improve what
you cannot me-measure, and you
cannot trust what you don't test.
That-- this statement applies everywhere.
It's not just for AI.
I'm just calling it out because
evals is the most critical piece to
think about when you are building AI.
So how to think about evals?
There are different frameworks for evals
out in the world, so pick any of them.
It's not like one is the best
or other, others are not.
But what is the right mental
model to think about AI?
So most of the evals for AI is…
Since AI is non-deterministic, you
cannot write a deterministic test.
You again have to write a
non-deterministic test using another LLM.
So a very basic example is
Let's say you ask your AI what is the
capital of France, and it came up and said
the the capital of France is New Delhi.
So you just throw that entire user--
entire message to a different LLM,
maybe a different LLM, not the same LLM.
So if you're using Opus or Sonnet for
that, let's say you throw it to OpenAI
and ask it, "Is the answer even correct?
Is the answer even grounded?" And it
can come back and say "The answer is
not correct because the capital of
France is Paris and not New Delhi."
That's a very basic example.
There are different eval checks that
are available out in their world.
They check for if your AI is
emitting any toxic answers in your
response, if your AI is drifting
from what you have expected it to.
So you can write different tests using
LLM as a judge to ask a different LLM
whether, how is my current AI doing?
So in order to think of evals,
it's just like again your normal
testing software pipeline.
So you should have a regression evals
in your CI pipeline or a CD pipeline.
So basically, whenever you're making
changes in your agent, it could be
you are fine-tuning the temperature,
you are making changes in the system
prompt, you are switching the model.
It could be anything.
So if you have a pre-quality gate before
it goes to production, you will be able to
catch regressions much sooner than later
when you deploy it to your customers.
Once it goes to production
You should definitely
think about telemetry.
When I say telemetry, like
when it goes to production
It will-- The production is like you can
run evals on your logs of your agent.
You can run evals on the
traces of your agent.
Basically, you should definitely
capture what the agent is doing
at every step in production.
And again, throw an LLM as a judge to it
that the user is asking some question,
and I am not answering according to the
question, or the user seems frustrated.
For example, we have a very basic eval,
we call it user temperament, and we
have a very basic system prompt to call
out, does the user seem frustrated?
Is the user typing in caps?
Is the user repeating the
same question again and again?
So these are some of the signals you
should start with to hint whether
your AI is working good or not.
And then you can dig deeper more
into how you can test it better.
And yeah, the idea is to shift left.
The idea is to shift
left any testing you do.
Again, be it AI, be it non-AI.
Yep.
The last piece for -- I'll start.
So the last piece for evals where it
makes it different from unit tests is you
-- Let's say you have hundred unit tests, and
you always want your hundred unit tests
to pass whenever you're shipping software.
If one of them fails, you go and fix it.
It's a bit different with evals.
You should think about evals as the
dataset you have where you are evaluating
your AI, everything should not pass.
The reason I say that is, if you're
improving your AI, you wouldn't
know whether it is improving.
So if you have seen all the benchmarks out
there in the world, like SWE benchmark,
where all the models evaluate that we
are able to crack eighty-eight percent on
the leaderboard out of hundred percent.
That means they're not able to
pass hundred percent, but they
are able to measure that I am at
eighty-eight percent right now.
I make some changes to it so that
I would be able to know whether
I'm going from eighty-eight to
eighty-seven or eighty-nine.
So that's the difference
I'm trying to call out.
If you have evals defined in a way that
you think of them as benchmarks, like
those hundred unit test cases, out of
hundred, if eighty are passing, now
anytime you're making changes to your
agent, if it is going from eighty to
eighty-five, you know it is improving.
If it is going from eighty to
seventy-five, you mean it is regressing.
So that's the difference in
the mental model when you think
about evals versus unit tests.
Yeah, a benchmark without bad
tests cannot measure progress.
It can only measure perfection
what you have configured before.
The second piece is
Whenever your evals are
failing, it means it's a signal.
It means whenever your eval is
failing in production, whenever a
user is frustrated, you get a signal.
You get a particular data set, you get
a particular behavior where you have
seen that agent is not working right.
So you turn it into a feedback loop
so that you put that test in your CI
now, so that now whenever next time
you are making changes to the agent,
the same issue does not happen again.
So it's like it's any failure
you are having in your production
system, it becomes a new test
case, new eval test case.
You add it to your benchmark, and you
are reaching towards a self-healing AI.
It-- You are automatically improving your
AI, looking at failures in the production,
and improving your benchmarks one by one.
On to the last piece, the most boring
piece which a lot of guys skip,
but the most important piece for
enterprise is kind-- kind-kind of
divided into four different sections.
Who did it?
What happened?
How did it happen?
Why did it happen?
So who did it is you're defining the
right access control on what an agent
can do versus what an agent cannot do.
I cannot just give it the entire set
of tools to the agent and ima- and
just hope that it would work great.
I would definitely want to
control what an agent can do.
So for example, I gave it a GitHub MCP,
and GitHub MCP has some tools to create
users, some tools to delete tokens, some
tools to delete branches or delete PRs.
I shouldn't even give access to
all of those tools to my agent.
So that is the one piece, basically
reducing the scope and the surface
of access you're giving your agent,
basically defining who can do what.
The second is the guardrails.
How do you protect what data
is used and where it flows?
So there are different types
of guardrails that exist.
First, starting from the top is the
PII detect- detection and reduction.
So if
for e- for example, if you're talking
about what is my Aadhaar number, what is
my email ID, what is my address, should
not be sending all of these sensitive
data to LLMs because enterprises care
a lot about what sensitive data are
being sent to LLM versus what is not.
So this comes under the right privacy
guardrails, the right data guardrails,
the right data residency guardrails.
Data residency, by data res- residency
for example, a very good example is if,
let's say you have a customer in Europe.
Europe has a very strict compliance.
You cannot send the data out
from Europe to any other region.
So I should make sure that all the
data I'm talking with AI is only
being accessed from the EU ecosystem
and not from outside of EU ecosystem.
The third piece is enforcing
how AI behaves in real time.
Some content safety filters, some
toxicness fil-filters things like those.
And the last piece is even if you
do all of this, let's say something
happened, something you're trying
to debug an incident, or you're
trying to figure out why it happened,
who caused it, and all of it.
If you don't have the right
auditability, what is happening, if
you don't have the right traceability,
you won't be able to debug it back
on who did it, how it happened.
Did agent do it?
Did you do it?
How did agent do it?
So you should definitely think about
full audit trails of what the actions
agent is taking, what are the different
model versions it is using at that
time, what are the different tool
calls the agent is making, and comply
to all of the different compliance
systems that exist in the world.
Again, with the code, ending with
the code is context is the new code,
governance is the new runtime because
governance is only applied at runtime.
Governance is not defined
when you're writing code.
Governance is only applied when your
agents are running, and you have to
put the right guardrails at runtime.
Just to summarize the entire enterprise
AI stack, starting with context, the new
code defines what AI knows, why it acts.
The first most important piece for your AI
to not hallucinate, to keep it grounded,
and with the knowledge graph and all.
The knowledge graph is the compiler.
It translates your complete
organization knowledge into a
usable structure like a graph.
So
it heavily helps in the
context engineering.
Instead of AI figuring it out, you throw
a graph, you throw a query layer at it,
and it gets better at querying your data.
The third is the governance.
The AI is running.
How do you govern it?
How do you make sure that it is
not going rogue, it is not bringing
down your production databases?
And the last piece, the most
important piece when you are def--
building AI is the testing of AI.
How do you measure trust, performance?
How do you know your AI is failing in
production and users are facing issues?
Because you cannot build an AI, the
most perfect AI in the first shot.
It will work fine in demos, it will
f- work fine on, on your laptops,
it will work fine on your QA, but it
might not work fine on production.
So it, it should always be
a continuous feedback loop.
You build AI, you deploy it, let the
regression test run, you ship it,
you constantly watch it, see what
is failing, come back as a feedback
loop, fix it, then keep doing that.
So it's like you complete the entire
circle of building your AI, and
you will eventually reach a stage
where it is like a self-healing AI.
That's it.
That's it from my side.
Thank, thanks a lot